# Rafael Massahiro Yassue

Blacksburg, VA, USA

**८** +1 540 418 5714 **▼** rafael.yassue@gmail.com **□** rafael-massahiro-yassue **○** <u>RafaelYassue</u>

Website

## RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am a Ph.D. candidate with experience in plant breeding, field experimentation, quantitative genetics, statistical modeling, phenomics, and genomics. My line of research is connecting genomics, high-throughput phenotyping, and quantitative genetics to plant breeding. My goal is to solve challenges by applying multidisciplinary approaches. Furthermore, I continuously improve myself in communication, teamwork, and leadership.

## **EDUCATION**

Virginia Tech	$2021-{ m Present}$
Visiting scholar	Blacksburg, United States
Luiz de Queiroz College of Agriculture - University of São Paulo	${\bf 2018-Present}$
Ph.D., Genetics and Plant Breeding	Piracicaba, Brazil
Luiz de Queiroz College of Agriculture - University of São Paulo	2016 - 2018
M.S., Genetics and Plant Breeding	Piracicaba, Brazil
Western Paraná State University - Unioeste	2011 - 2015
B.Sc. Agronomic Engineering	Mal. C. Rondon, Brazil

# **SKILLS**

• Quantitative genetics	• Statistical modeling	• Phenomics	• R, Python, and Julia
• Plant breeding	• Image processing	• Genomics	• Markdown, GitHub,
			and LAT <sub>E</sub> X

## **LANGUAGES**

• Portuguese	(native)	• English (advance	d) •	Spanish (	(Basic	

#### EXPERIENCE

Coordinator of plant breeding study group, Gvenck	2019
Coordinated the group's activities	Piracicaba, Brazil
Member of plant breeding study group, Gvenck	2016 - 2019
Promote discussions on relevant plant breeding issues, and soft skills improvement	Piracicaba, Brazil
Academic internship, Soybean breeding, Esalq	2015
Field experimentation, scientific discussion, and data analysis	Piracicaba, Brazil
Intern, Soybean breeding, Coodetec	2013-2014
Hands-on experience in an industry breeding program	Cascavel, Brazil
Undergraduate Research, Plant breeding, Unioeste	2011 - 2015
Learning in methods of research and development of scientific thought	Mal. C. Rondon, Brazil

## ADDITIONAL TRAINING

• Introdução ao aprendizado de máquinas com Python	2021
• Workshop on Analysis of Breeding Experiments using ASReml-R	2020
• Workshop on Crop Growth Models Applied for Plant Breeding	2020
• Treinamento genotype to phenotype models in plant breeding	2019
• System biology and gene networks inference: application to livestock	2019
• IV Workshop on Longitudinal and Incomplete Data	2018
• Quantitative Genetics and Genomics	2018
• New methodologies for high-resolution mapping and development of molecular	2017

## **PRESENTATIONS**

- An assessment of the predictive ability of plant growth-promoting bacteria inoculation status and shoot dry
  mass using hyperspectral images in tropical maize. ASA, CSSA, and SSSA International Annual Meetings.
  Virtual 2021
- A low-cost greenhouse-based high-throughput phenotyping platform for genetic studies in maize under inoculation with plant growth-promoting bacteria. NAPB Annual Meeting.

  Virtual 2021
- Melhoramento do Milho. Aula da disciplina: Introdução à Engenharia Agronômica. ESALQ. Virtual 2021
- Investigating the genetic architecture of the interaction between tropical maize and plant growth-promoting bacteria via high-throughput phenotyping. Translation Plant Science-Discussion Group (TPS-DG). Virginia Tech.
- Genetic architecture of the interaction between tropical maize and plant growth-promoting bacteria via high-throughput phenotyping. Genomics and machine learning discussion group. Virginia Tech.Virtual 2021

# **PUBLICATIONS**

- Galli G, et al. Automated Machine Learning: a case study of genomic "image-based" prediction in maize hybrids. Frontiers in Plant Science, 2022. doi
- Yassue RM, et al. On the genetic architecture in a public tropical maize panel of the symbiosis between corn and plant growth-promoting bacteria aiming to improve plant resilience. Molecular Breeding, 2021. doi
- Yassue RM et al. A low-cost greenhouse-based high-throughput phenotyping platform for genetic studies: a case study in maize under inoculation with plant growth-promoting bacteria bioRxiv (Preprint), 2021. doi
- Yassue RM, et al. CV-α: designing validations sets to increase the precision and enable multiple comparison tests in genomic prediction studies. Euphytica. 2021. doi
- Souza RS, et al. Combining ability for the improvement of vegetable soybean, Agronomy Journal. 2020. doi
- Espolador FG, et al. Assessing tolerance to Asian soybean rust in soybean inbred lines from exotic and adapted crosses. Euphytica, 2020. doi
- Yassue RM, et al. Uni and multivariate approaches for diallel analysis in early generation trials for soybean tolerance to rust. Bragantia. 2019. doi

#### REFERENCES

- Prof. Dr. Gota Morota Assistant Professor of quantitative genetics at Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University morota@vt.edu
- Prof. Dr. Roberto Fritsche-Neto Senior Scientist at International Rice Research Institute r.fritscheneto@irri.org
- Prof. Dr. James Chen Assistant Professor of Animal Data Sciences at Virginia Tech niche@vt.edu